<?xml version="1.0" encoding = "iso-8859-1" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xsl/page.xsl"?>
<page pid='r00' name='modglossaries' style='assets/css/layout.css' xsl='assets/xsl/page.xsl' next=''>
	<content type='resource'>
		<moduleheading>Welcome to DOHA Essentials</moduleheading>
		<topicheading indexed="no">Utilities</topicheading>
		<pageheading >Glossary</pageheading>
	    <paragraph >
		<paragraph>Achnowledgement: </paragraph>
		<paragraph>Content for this module has been sourced from the APSC Induction Module (July 2007 -updated July 2008)</paragraph>
		<table width="700" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="1">
	      <th>Term</th>
	        <th>Definition</th>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Accountability </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Individuals, organisations, and the community are answerable for decisions and having meaningful mechanisms in place to ensure adherence to all applicable standards. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Administrative Appeals Tribunal </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The Administrative Appeals Tribunal provides independent review of a wide range of administrative decisions made by the Australian government and some non-government bodies. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Administrative Arrangements Order </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A formal document issued by the scheduled Executive Council, which assigns responsibility for legislation and functions to departments of state. They can cause administrative change when functions are moved from one department to another. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Agencies </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Agencies may include departments, executive agencies or statutory agencies, as defined by the <em>Public Service Act 1999.</em></p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Agency head </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The agency head (or Secretary in the case of the 18 portfolio departments) is responsible to the relevant Minister for the efficient, effective and ethical management of their organisation. They are the employer on behalf of the Commonwealth of the staff in the organisation. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Annual report </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The <em>Public Service Act 1999</em> requires that at the end of each financial year agencies must prepare an annual report on their activities during the preceding year. The report is presented to the agency's Minister, who then presents it to the Parliament. Annual reports generally provide information about the agency's business intent, performance, achievement highlights and other activities. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Appropriations </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Appropriations are authorisations granted by the Parliament to spend monies from the Consolidated Revenue Fund for a particular purpose. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> APS Classification </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> All positions within the APS are based on a classification structure aligned to work level standards. These classifications determine salary entitlements. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> APS Code of Conduct </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The Code of Conduct is a public statement of the minimum standards of behaviour and conduct expected of individuals who work in the APS. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> APS Values </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The APS Values articulate the Parliament's expectations of public servants in terms of high performance and high standards of behaviour. The principles of good public administration are embodied in the APS Values. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Assignment of duties </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Assignment of duties refers to the action of the agency head in determining the duties of an employee. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Auditor-General </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The Auditor-General is an independent officer of the Parliament, who undertakes independent audits of financial probity and performance of the APS in selected areas, and makes recommendations to Parliament. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Australian Workplace Agreement </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> An Australian Workplace Agreement, or AWA, is a negotiated agreement between an individual and the agency, which details agreed working conditions for that individual. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Broadbanding </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Broadbanding involves the classification of a position across two or more general classification levels. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Business activity </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> An umbrella term covering all the functions, activities and transactions of an organisation and its employees. Business activity is a broad term used within public administration, non-profit and other activities.</p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Capability </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A term that describes what people have to be able to do and how they have to behave in order to carry out their work successfully. Capable people are those who do the work well, achieving their objectives and meeting the required standards of performance. Capabilities' is a term that embraces both competency and competence. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Central agency </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Central agencies have particular APS-wide responsibilities for setting the legislative, financial and employment frameworks within which each agency operates. </p></td>
        </tr>
		<tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Chief Executive Instructions </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p>Chief Executives may issue instructions on any matter that promotes the efficient, effective and ethical use of the Commonwealth resources for which the Chief Executive is responsible, thus dealing with all issues relating to public money, public property and other resources.

</p></td>
        </tr>
		<tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Coaching </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The practice of instructing, demonstrating, directing, and prompting participants. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Code of Conduct </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The APS Code of Conduct in included in section 13 of the <em>Public Service Act 1999</em>, and articulates the minimum standards of behaviour and conduct expected of individuals who work in the APS. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Collective agreement </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A collective agreement outlines the conditions that apply to all employees in the agency who have elected to be covered by that collective agreement. The terms and conditions of the agreement cover aspects including rates of pay, superannuation contributions, leave entitlements, working hours, and performance management. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Commonwealth Authorities and Companies Act 1997 (CAC Act) </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The CAC Act contains detailed rules about reporting and accountability, and deals with other matters such as banking and investment and the conduct of officers. For Commonwealth <strong>authorities</strong>, the CAC Act contains detailed rules about reporting and accountability, and deals with other matters such as banking and investment and the conduct of officers. For Commonwealth <strong>companies</strong>, the CAC Act contains reporting and other requirements that apply in addition to the requirements of the <em>Corporations Act 2001</em>. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Commonwealth Budget </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Sets out the fiscal and economic outlook for Australia, and includes expenditure and revenue estimates for the current financial year and three forward years. It shows the Government's social and political priorities, and how the Government intends to achieve these. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Commonwealth Ombudsman </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The Commonwealth Ombudsman considers and investigates complaints from people who believe they have been treated unfairly or unreasonably by an Australian government department or agency. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Competency </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> This relates to all the work related personal attributes, knowledge, skills and values that a person draws upon to do their work well. Competencies are the behavioural dimensions that affect job performance and include such characteristics as interpersonal skills, leadership, analytical skills and achievement orientation. In HR terminology, there is a difference between competency and competence. Competency' is a person related concept or refers to the dimensions of behaviour line behind competent performance. Competence' is a work related concept or refers to new areas of work at which the person is competent. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Contact officer </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The contact officer is the person who has been nominated to answer queries, or provide further information. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Core entitlements </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Core entitlements are entitlements which are available to all APS employees, regardless of which agency they are employed by, or whether they are covered by a collective agreement or an Australian Workplace Agreement. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Delegate </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A person to whom a power is delegated under an express power of delegation, for example, by the Minister or agency head. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Direct sourcing </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A procurement process, available only under certain defined circumstances, in which an agency may contact a single potential supplier or suppliers of its choice, and for which only a limited set of mandatory procurement procedures apply. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Duty statement </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The duty statement describes the role, key tasks and responsibilities individuals are required to perform in the job. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Efficiency </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The best use of resources to further the aims of the organisations with a commitment to evidence-based strategies for improvement. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Employee assistance programme </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The Employee Assistance Program (EAP) service provides a free, confidential and professional workplace counselling service to staff and their immediate families. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> e-permanence </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A comprehensive range of policies, standards, guidelines and training developed and maintained by the National archives of Australia to facilitate the capture and management of records and other business information to meet accountability requirements. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Executive agencies </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Executive agencies are non-statutory bodies established by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister. The agency head is appointed by, and directly accountable to, the Minister responsible for the agency. The purpose of the executive agency structure is to provide a degree of separation from departmental management where that is appropriate to the functions of the agency and something less than a statutory authority is warranted. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p><em> Financial Management and Accountability Act 1997</em> (FMA Act) </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The <em>Financial Management and Accountability Act 1997</em> (FMA Act) provides a framework for the proper management of public money and public property. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Freedom of information </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The <em>Freedom of Information Act</em><em>1982</em> requires Commonwealth agencies to make available a range of information about their operations and powers affecting members of the public including manuals and documents used to make decisions. </p>
              <p> Access to all documents in the possession of the Government is not possible for confidentiality purposes. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Governance </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Encompasses how an organisation is managed, its corporate and other structures, its culture, its policies and strategies, and lines of accountability. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Human resources</p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Human Resources (HR) relates to planning and management of personnel issues. HR practices include workforce planning, recruitment and selection, performance management, learning and development, reward and recognition, workplace diversity, and occupational health and safety.</p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Identified position </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Some jobs in the APS are known as identified positions'. These are the ones which require specific knowledge and understanding of Indigenous Australian cultures and issues, and the ability to communicate sensitively and effectively with Indigenous communities. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Integrated Leadership System </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The Integrated Leadership System (ILS) provides capability development guidance for individuals and agencies in the form of descriptions and behaviours for all levels in the APS. It contains practical tools for individuals and agencies to chart leadership development. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Integrity </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Acting impartially, ethically and in the interests of the agency, and not misusing information acquired through a position of trust. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Leadership </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p>  Leadership from the top is critical to achieving an agency wide commitment to good governance. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Learning and development </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Learning and development refers to learning activities on-the-job as well as more formal off-the-job activities. Seminars, conferences, classroom training courses, leadership programmes, academic study, in-house programmes are all included. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Machinery of Government </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The term Machinery of Government' is used to describe a variety of organisational or functional changes affecting the Commonwealth, such as the creation of a new statutory agency or executive agency or abolition of such agencies, or the movement of functions in and out of the APS. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Management Advisory Committee </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The Management Advisory Committee (MAC) is a forum of Secretaries and Agency Heads established under the <em>Public Service Act 1999</em> to advise the Australian Government on matters relating to the management of the Australian Public Service (APS). </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Mandatory qualifications </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Some positions require specific qualifications/skills, which applicants must meet to be considered for the position. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Mentoring </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The process of providing guidance and advice at various stages in someone's career. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Merit-based assessment </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A competitive merit-based assessment determines an applicant's suitability for a role by making a comparative evaluation of available evidence against predetermined job requirements. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Misconduct </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Misconduct is a generic term which refers to an action or behaviour by an APS employee, who is determined to have breached the APS code of conduct. Prior to such a determination, the action or behaviour is referred to as suspected misconduct. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Mobility </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Mobility relates to promotion and transfers between agencies, as well as movements in and out of the APS. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Movement </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Movement refers to a move of an ongoing employee between agencies. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> New policy proposals </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Ministers' proposals to Cabinet recommending the adoption of a new initiative or change to existing programs. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Non-ongoing employee </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A non-ongoing employee is an employee who is engaged for either a specified term of for the duration of a specified task of or duties that are the regular or intermittent as mentioned in sections 22(2)(b) and (c) of the PS Act. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Ongoing employee </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Ongoing employee is an APS employee engaged in accordance with section 22(2)(a) of the Public Service Act. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Online learning </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Delivery of educational content via a Web browser over the internet or intranet, including via email, bulletin boards, and discussion groups. May also cover a wide set of applications and processes of e-learning, computer-based learning, virtual classrooms, and digital collaboration. It includes the delivery of content via Internet, intranet/extranet, audio and videotape, satellite, and CD-ROM. However, many organisations only consider it as a network-enabled transfer of skills and knowledge. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Open tender process </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A procurement procedure in which a request for tender is published, inviting all businesses that satisfy the conditions for participation to submit tenders. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Outcomes </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p>Outcomes are results or impacts the government wants to achieve.</p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Outputs </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Outputs are the goods and services produced by agencies on behalf of the government or external organisations or individuals, for example, infrastructure funding for the schools system. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Outsourcing </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Outsourcing, or competitive tendering and contracting, refers to an arrangement whereby an APS agency has an activity, function or service, which was previously undertaken in-house, performed by a private sector provider or another public sector organisation. Under such an arrangement, the original agency retains overall responsibility and accountability for the activity, function or service. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p><em> Parliamentary Service Act 1999 </em></p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Act under which Department of Parliamentary Services staff are employed. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Performance management </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A method of measuring performance at both the organisational and individual level. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Portfolio Budget Statements </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Portfolio Budget Statements (PBS) are documents that portfolio departments publish explaining each agency's source and use of funds by outcome. The purpose of the portfolio budget statement is to inform senators and members of Parliament of the proposed allocation of resources to government outcomes by agencies within each portfolio. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Procurement </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Procurement encompasses the whole process of acquiring property or services. It begins when an agency has identified a need and decided on its procurement requirement. Procurement continues through the processes of risk assessment, seeking and evaluating alternative solutions, contract award, delivery of and payment for the property or services, and, where relevant, the ongoing management of the contract and consideration of options related to the contract. Procurement also extends to the ultimate disposal of property at the end of its useful life. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Promotion </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Promotion means the ongoing assignment of duties to an ongoing employee at a higher classification than the one held by the employee. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p><em> Public Service Act 1999 </em></p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Sets out expectations of how the people who administer the Commonwealth will be employed, including how they will be engaged, how they will be managed, and expected standards of integrity and behaviour. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Public Service Gazette </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The Public Service Gazette contains notices required to be published under the <em>Public Service Act 1999</em> and associated legislation. These notices include administrative matters as well as employment opportunities, movements to APS employment opportunities and promotions within the Australian Public Service. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Request for tender </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A published notice inviting businesses satisfying the conditions for participation to submit a tender in accordance with requirements of the request for tender and other tender documentation. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Risk management </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Risk management involves the systematic identification, analysis, treatment, and where appropriate, acceptance of risks. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Secretary </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Secretaries head the 18 portfolio departments and are responsible to their Minister both for departmental management and for advising the Minister in all matters relating to the department; including policy advice, implementation and administration. They must also assist their Minister to fulfil his or her accountability obligations to the Parliament. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Selection criteria </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Selection criteria describe the skills, experience and personal qualities needed to do a job effectively. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Selection documentation </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> This is the package of information available from an agency that provides more details about an advertised position. It usually and includes a duty statement and selection criteria. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Selection panel </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A selection panel is a small group of people who assess job applicants for a position and make a recommendation about the best person for the job. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Select tender process </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A procurement procedure in which the procuring agency selects which potential suppliers are invited to submit tenders. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Senate Estimates </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A twice yearly process where Senate committees examine the estimates of proposed annual expenditure of government departments and authorities. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Senior Executive Leadership Capability Framework </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> This Senior Executive Leadership Capability Framework seeks to establish a shared understanding of the critical success factors for performance in APS leadership roles. It identifies the five core criteria for high performance by senior executives. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Senior Executive Service </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The Secretary or agency head is supported by a senior management team, referred to as the Senior Executive Service (SES). The SES has key leadership responsibilities for the management of professional expertise and policy advice, leading and encouraging cooperation across agencies, modelling the APS Values and promoting compliance with the Code of Conduct. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Short-listing </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Short-listing is the process a selection panel goes through in assessing written applications and making a short list of the applicants they want to interview or further assess for the job. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Skills analysis </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A skills analysis breaks down a job's components into separate tasks and considers exactly how the job and its tasks are done. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Special appropriations </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Special appropriations provide authority for amounts to be drawn from the Consolidated Revenue Fund for particular purposes, for example, to finance a particular project or a programme such as social security payments. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> State of the Service report </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> The Australian Public Service Commissioner must provide a report each year to the Minister for presentation to the Parliament on the state of the Australian Public Service. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Statutory agencies </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Statutory agencies are bodies established by legislation that specifies the extent to which the agency staff are part of the APS. The enabling legislation also sets out the arrangements for the appointment and termination of the agency head and their specific powers, responsibilities and accountability requirements. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Stewardship </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Using every opportunity to enhance the value of the public assets and institutions that have been entrusted to care. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Tender </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> A submission from a potential supplier making an offer to perform a procurement in response to requests for tender or invitation to tender. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Tender documentation </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Documentation provided to businesses to enable them to understand and assess the requirements of the procuring agency and to prepare appropriate and responsive submissions. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Transfer </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> With reference to job selection, a transfer is usually defined as movement at level; either within an agency or between agencies. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Transparency </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Clear roles and responsibilities and clear procedures for decision-making and the exercise of power. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Whistleblowing </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Whistleblowing is a generic term which refers to an APS employee making report of breaches or alleged breaches of the APS Code of Conduct to an authorised person. </p></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td width="151" valign="top"><p> Whole of government </p></td>
          <td width="425" valign="top"><p> Whole of government denotes public service agencies working across portfolio boundaries to achieve a shared goal and an integrated government response to particular issues. Approaches can be formal and informal. They can focus on policy development, programme management and service delivery. </p></td>
        </tr>
    </table>
	</paragraph>
	</content>
</page>